<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Mexico on Lopeztel&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://lopeztel.xyz/blog/tags/mexico/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mexico on Lopeztel&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 May 2021 19:26:16 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lopeztel.xyz/blog/tags/mexico/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Mexican Food (Part 2)</title>
      <link>https://lopeztel.xyz/blog/2021/05/10/mexican-food-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 May 2021 19:26:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lopeztel.xyz/blog/2021/05/10/mexican-food-part-2/</guid>
      <description>This is a bit of a follow-up on my previous rant on Mexican food and its representation abroad, see the previous entry, since last time I’ve tried to show “the way” to my Norwegian friends and I thought it would be nice to document the process.
I’ve also written about food during some holidays, see:
Day of the Dead away from Mexico Day of the Epiphany away from Mexico The first time I cooked something remotely close to real Mexican food had to wait until I got a care package, after Christmas-New Year’s, it contained some traditional sweets (long gone by the time of writing of this entry), some Mezcal (I like to describe the flavor as “smoked” Tequila) and some flasks of Mole and an assortment of dry peppers</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day of the Epiphany (Three Kings’ Day?) away from Mexico</title>
      <link>https://lopeztel.xyz/blog/2021/01/09/day-of-the-epiphany-three-kings-day-away-from-mexico/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jan 2021 09:08:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lopeztel.xyz/blog/2021/01/09/day-of-the-epiphany-three-kings-day-away-from-mexico/</guid>
      <description>Following up on my series “Celebrating holidays away from Mexico”, after entries such as: a rant about Mexican food on independence day and day of the dead
January 6th is Día de Reyes, the last date of what we Mexicans know as the Guadalupe – Reyes marathon (which is, in short, an extended holiday period for eating and drinking that starts on December 12th)
Being away from home and still a bit bitter about not being able to go back home for the holidays because of COVID-19, I contacted my baker friend and ordered Rosca de Reyes (roughly translates to King’s baguel I guess).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day of the dead away from Mexico</title>
      <link>https://lopeztel.xyz/blog/2020/11/02/day-of-the-dead-away-from-mexico/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 18:36:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lopeztel.xyz/blog/2020/11/02/day-of-the-dead-away-from-mexico/</guid>
      <description>I usually like to hate on Facebook but I’ve got to admit it is useful if used responsibly, this time thanks to it, I found out that a mexican baker had moved to town and I managed to get “Pan de Muerto” (Dead bread?).
I feel like I have to describe it for non-mexicans: for starters, it’s not made of dead people 😛
It’s like a not so dense bun (with a twist of orange) and covered in sugar.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
