<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Reflections on Lopeztel&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://lopeztel.xyz/blog/tags/reflections/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Reflections on Lopeztel&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 May 2021 19:26:16 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lopeztel.xyz/blog/tags/reflections/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Mexican Food (Part 2)</title>
      <link>https://lopeztel.xyz/blog/2021/05/10/mexican-food-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 May 2021 19:26:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lopeztel.xyz/blog/2021/05/10/mexican-food-part-2/</guid>
      <description>This is a bit of a follow-up on my previous rant on Mexican food and its representation abroad, see the previous entry, since last time I’ve tried to show “the way” to my Norwegian friends and I thought it would be nice to document the process.
I’ve also written about food during some holidays, see:
 Day of the Dead away from Mexico Day of the Epiphany away from Mexico  The first time I cooked something remotely close to real Mexican food had to wait until I got a care package, after Christmas-New Year’s, it contained some traditional sweets (long gone by the time of writing of this entry), some Mezcal (I like to describe the flavor as “smoked” Tequila) and some flasks of Mole and an assortment of dry peppers</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day of the Epiphany (Three Kings’ Day?) away from Mexico</title>
      <link>https://lopeztel.xyz/blog/2021/01/09/day-of-the-epiphany-three-kings-day-away-from-mexico/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jan 2021 09:08:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lopeztel.xyz/blog/2021/01/09/day-of-the-epiphany-three-kings-day-away-from-mexico/</guid>
      <description>Following up on my series “Celebrating holidays away from Mexico”, after entries such as: a rant about Mexican food on independence day and day of the dead
January 6th is Día de Reyes, the last date of what we Mexicans know as the Guadalupe – Reyes marathon (which is, in short, an extended holiday period for eating and drinking that starts on December 12th)
Being away from home and still a bit bitter about not being able to go back home for the holidays because of COVID-19, I contacted my baker friend and ordered Rosca de Reyes (roughly translates to King’s baguel I guess).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Christmas 2020</title>
      <link>https://lopeztel.xyz/blog/2020/12/29/christmas-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2020 19:11:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lopeztel.xyz/blog/2020/12/29/christmas-2020/</guid>
      <description>This is meant to be a reflection on spending Christmas alone in one of the worst years for the planet in general.
I think it’s basically beating on a dead horse to say that 2020 has been horrible in general due to COVID-19, everyone has had it tough for a lot of reasons, from the worst (having lost a loved one or health issues) to the minor annoyances (like working from home).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A little more than a year living in Norway</title>
      <link>https://lopeztel.xyz/blog/2020/12/15/a-little-more-than-a-year-living-in-norway/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 20:10:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lopeztel.xyz/blog/2020/12/15/a-little-more-than-a-year-living-in-norway/</guid>
      <description>As the title suggests, it’s been a little over a year since I moved to Norway for work… It’s been a challenging year to say the least, and not only because of COVID-19.
For starters, it’s been hard to get used to this weird country’s ways (and I mean this in the most endearing way), from personal space, weather and language to food (I am Mexican and I cannot stress the importance of food enough, see my previous entry for reference).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fishing as a new hobby</title>
      <link>https://lopeztel.xyz/blog/2020/11/28/fishing-as-a-new-hobby/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2020 19:04:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lopeztel.xyz/blog/2020/11/28/fishing-as-a-new-hobby/</guid>
      <description>For some time now, starting from spring last year, I’ve been going out to fish (from the fjord’s shore) with 2 of my friends here.
Let’s just say that we’re not very good at this, a lot of our lures/hooks have been lost to seaweed and even bad knots that came loose while throwing (that one was me by the way 😛 )
Only one I managed to catch something, gutting, bleeding and cutting the fish was an experience and it makes you appreciate the convenience of supermarkets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Privacy Resources and ongoing translation efforts</title>
      <link>https://lopeztel.xyz/blog/2020/11/23/privacy-resources-and-ongoing-translation-efforts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 16:53:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lopeztel.xyz/blog/2020/11/23/privacy-resources-and-ongoing-translation-efforts/</guid>
      <description>Humanetech Translation Project Otherwise known as HTP (I personally prefer HTTP 😛 ), is a little project that started on the Humane Tech Community forum after my little comment about privacy related content available mostly in English, see this entry for context.
The project has officially started and is looking for translators, so if anyone is interested please head here, apparently we’ve gathered quite a few translators already but it’s always nice to have more!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day of the dead away from Mexico</title>
      <link>https://lopeztel.xyz/blog/2020/11/02/day-of-the-dead-away-from-mexico/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 18:36:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lopeztel.xyz/blog/2020/11/02/day-of-the-dead-away-from-mexico/</guid>
      <description>I usually like to hate on Facebook but I’ve got to admit it is useful if used responsibly, this time thanks to it, I found out that a mexican baker had moved to town and I managed to get “Pan de Muerto” (Dead bread?).
I feel like I have to describe it for non-mexicans: for starters, it’s not made of dead people 😛
It’s like a not so dense bun (with a twist of orange) and covered in sugar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some thoughts on the weekend hike</title>
      <link>https://lopeztel.xyz/blog/2020/10/20/some-thoughts-on-the-weekend-hike/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2020 19:51:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lopeztel.xyz/blog/2020/10/20/some-thoughts-on-the-weekend-hike/</guid>
      <description>This weekend was fun, on Sunday some friends invited me to tag along on their weekend hike. All this happened because the company I work for decided to donate money to a charitable cause, the money amount was proportional to the distance logged by all its employees so that was motivation for us to run, walk or hike during the weekend.
The hike was long (11+ Km), it took us around 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Convenience vs Privacy (Round 2)</title>
      <link>https://lopeztel.xyz/blog/2020/09/30/convenience-vs-privacy-round-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2020 17:55:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lopeztel.xyz/blog/2020/09/30/convenience-vs-privacy-round-2/</guid>
      <description>Context For a while now I’ve been trying to find ways to convey the risks of social media and the importance of privacy to my non-tech savvy family members, in a previous entry I went over getting away from WhatsApp (Facebook really) and using element connected to my own self hosted synapse server.
The Social Dilemma Two weeks ago I watched The Social Dilemma on Netflix, which I really enjoyed. To elaborate further these are my main take aways:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mexican food</title>
      <link>https://lopeztel.xyz/blog/2020/09/15/mexican-food/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 16:55:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lopeztel.xyz/blog/2020/09/15/mexican-food/</guid>
      <description>Context I am writing this entry because today is September 15th, almost Mexican Independence day. Fun fact: The whole thing really started on September 16th, 210 years ago but to this day is celebrated on the night of the 15th because one of our presidents wanted to celebrate his birthday at the same time. See Porfirio Diaz for more details.
This entry is a bit of a rant about living abroad and what everyone calls “Mexican food”</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Convenience vs Privacy (Round 1)</title>
      <link>https://lopeztel.xyz/blog/2020/09/04/convenience-vs-privacy-round-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2020 19:13:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lopeztel.xyz/blog/2020/09/04/convenience-vs-privacy-round-1/</guid>
      <description>A brief summary: I’ve been looking into privacy friendly alternatives to software most of us use or used in our everyday lives. To be more precise, an alternative to WhatsApp for communication within my family. Long story short: I lost this one…
A while back I switched from WhatsApp to Signal and kind of forced my family to switch as well, however:
Signal requires a phone number and depends on centralized servers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FOSS Donations</title>
      <link>https://lopeztel.xyz/blog/2020/08/26/foss-donations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 16:58:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lopeztel.xyz/blog/2020/08/26/foss-donations/</guid>
      <description>Let me start by saying that the purpose of this entry is not to say “Look at how selfless I am for donating money to FOSS organizations or projects” so, with that in mind, I will not list any specific quantities because that is not the point I am trying to make. Having written the proper disclaimer, let’s get to it:
My preferences In the past month I have written about my projects and experiences with FOSS, self hosting and even digital art.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some thoughts on consumerism</title>
      <link>https://lopeztel.xyz/blog/2020/08/05/some-thoughts-on-consumerism/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2020 06:00:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lopeztel.xyz/blog/2020/08/05/some-thoughts-on-consumerism/</guid>
      <description>I like to keep up to date with the latest news on the consumer electronics market (newest phones, laptops and processors) and lately I’ve found myself thinking: “That looks like a great phone/laptop, I should get it”.
Then the thought that usually follows is “Maybe I don’t really need it”
That’s the thing, media constantly bombards us with ads to get new things/gadgets when we already own perfectly working devices…</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mexico – Quality of life and different perspectives</title>
      <link>https://lopeztel.xyz/blog/2020/07/30/mexico-quality-of-life-and-different-perspectives/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2020 20:18:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lopeztel.xyz/blog/2020/07/30/mexico-quality-of-life-and-different-perspectives/</guid>
      <description>OK, I am guilty of scrolling through Facebook even though I am on the Fediverse… I simply keep it because everyone else I care about does, anyway, on to the important stuff:
Every once in a while I see something worthwhile there, this time I saw two very interesting posts close to each other (in my timeline at least), these were shared by two different people, both Mexican like me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some thoughts on being productive</title>
      <link>https://lopeztel.xyz/blog/2020/07/28/some-thoughts-on-being-productive/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2020 20:16:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lopeztel.xyz/blog/2020/07/28/some-thoughts-on-being-productive/</guid>
      <description>This entry is going to be a bit more personal, I usually avoid all the touchy – feely subjects but there is something to be said about how we go about balancing our professional careers and private life.
Long story short, I think I work with brilliant people and lately I’ve been anxious about catching up and feeling a bit guilty whenever I catch myself at home being a couch potato.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My not so new job</title>
      <link>https://lopeztel.xyz/blog/2020/07/02/my-not-so-new-job/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2020 20:07:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lopeztel.xyz/blog/2020/07/02/my-not-so-new-job/</guid>
      <description>As mentioned in a previous entry, I started a new job in Norway last year, here are my thoughts so far:
First of all, a couple of interviews related to my position took place 3 weeks before my Master’s thesis was due, all that can be said about that is: lots of excitement, I remember getting results and figures the weekend before the final interview took place.
After a well deserved month of relaxation back home (Mexico), my first day on my new job was a week before the company’s Christmas party and it wasn’t long after that everything was slowing down and everyone was away from the office so not much time to get used to a new country and learn the ropes at the new workplace.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nice gestures</title>
      <link>https://lopeztel.xyz/blog/2020/06/26/nice-gestures/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2020 20:03:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lopeztel.xyz/blog/2020/06/26/nice-gestures/</guid>
      <description>Having being abroad and back home 2 times in the last 3 years have taught me that living in Mexico makes you take some things for granted:
 Family Excellent food Friends  Let’s just say that personal interactions have been… different, but not in a bad way.
I was always a bit of an oddball, antisocial even (for Mexican standards), but after accepting a job offer in November that led to moving to Norway, knowing just a handful of people in the city (from my Masters program), living alone and COVID-19 lock down, even I started to feel anxious and a bit depressed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some thoughts about convenience and COVID-19</title>
      <link>https://lopeztel.xyz/blog/2020/04/18/some-thoughts-about-convenience-and-covid-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Apr 2020 19:55:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lopeztel.xyz/blog/2020/04/18/some-thoughts-about-convenience-and-covid-19/</guid>
      <description>I was just recently thinking given the recent COVID-19 situation, the world is not ready to prioritize what is really important.
It feels like no one really notices importance of services like running water, electricity and above all medical care. What I see on the news nowadays leads me to believe that no one really cares about anything as long as we’re not affected.
No one cared about COVID-19 until we couldn’t go out, until our Amazon or Aliexpress and overall cheap stuff from China couldn’t reach us in time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Skiing and COVID-19</title>
      <link>https://lopeztel.xyz/blog/2020/03/13/skiing-and-covid-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Mar 2020 19:52:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lopeztel.xyz/blog/2020/03/13/skiing-and-covid-19/</guid>
      <description>Some random thoughts on a recent failed ski trip and the global pandemic
Skiing First things first, I have absolutely no clue on how to ski, zero experience whatsoever, so naturally I had to sign up for my company’s Ski trip. In total there were 37 people in the group.
We got to a cabin close to a ski resort after a four and a half hour drive on Wednesday, all went well except for some icy paths on the way but that is another story (just don’t do summer tires and front 2 wheel drive on them, you’ll suffer a lot)</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
