<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Selfhosting on Lopeztel&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://lopeztel.xyz/blog/tags/selfhosting/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Selfhosting on Lopeztel&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2022 19:37:10 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lopeztel.xyz/blog/tags/selfhosting/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Migrating from WordPress to Hugo</title>
      <link>https://lopeztel.xyz/blog/2022/08/22/from-wordpress-to-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2022 19:37:10 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lopeztel.xyz/blog/2022/08/22/from-wordpress-to-hugo/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been toying with the idea for a while, and now I finally found time to get to it (more like I used the project as an excuse to not go out and exercise :P)
The whole thing started with finding this blog post and realizing I could just host my own static website from my yunohost raspberrypi setup, so the journey began
I was gladly surprised by the fact that Hugo is easy to install in Arch or Arch based Linux distros (such as my main desktop&amp;rsquo;s Manjaro install):</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fooling around with bash scripts 2</title>
      <link>https://lopeztel.xyz/blog/2021/02/28/fooling-around-with-bash-scripts-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2021 13:20:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lopeztel.xyz/blog/2021/02/28/fooling-around-with-bash-scripts-2/</guid>
      <description>This is a follow-up to my previous entries: Fooling around with bash scripts, which I used as a base for Migration from Google Photos to Nextcloud and Piwigo
Since some of my old picture albums have old .mov, .mpg and .avi videos in them I decided to also convert them to .mp4 (piwigo can show them in the albums), so once again I tried came up with something to automate the task</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fooling around with bash scripts</title>
      <link>https://lopeztel.xyz/blog/2021/02/02/fooling-around-with-bash-scripts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 19:13:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lopeztel.xyz/blog/2021/02/02/fooling-around-with-bash-scripts/</guid>
      <description>I thought I would share 2 shell scripts that I’ve found useful, the first one allows me to to use my DSLR camera as a webcam and the second one allows me to batch resize and optimize images
Using DSLR as webcam This is probably most useful in COVID-19 times, found it a while back on YouTube (not a fan of the big G? Invidious or FreeTube are your friends), also here’s a blog post for more details.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My blogging journey so far</title>
      <link>https://lopeztel.xyz/blog/2021/01/21/my-blogging-journey-so-far/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2021 20:29:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lopeztel.xyz/blog/2021/01/21/my-blogging-journey-so-far/</guid>
      <description>I remember I started a blog in March last year (2019), it was a simple Writefreely blog,it looked like this:
It was simple, easy to use and you could follow it via mastodon, I wanted to engage a bit more with my fellow fedizens so I started looking into Wordpress around the same time I built my Raspberrypi 4 server and I found out that Wordpress was an app Yunohost had listed (it&amp;rsquo;s basically a one-click install but you require a dedicated domain) so I migrated, at the time that was easy, just downloaded all my previous posts in markdown and added them one by one (there weren&amp;rsquo;t that many).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thank you Yunohost (Part 2)</title>
      <link>https://lopeztel.xyz/blog/2020/12/12/thank-you-yunohost-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2020 09:52:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lopeztel.xyz/blog/2020/12/12/thank-you-yunohost-part-2/</guid>
      <description>This is a bit of a continuation on my previous thank you post, since I received a lot of help and it deserves proper credit, this post is to be taken as part thank you note and part summary of the whole SSL certificate issue ordeal:
First things first, in short Yunohost is an easy solution to get started with self hosting without dealing with the more technical side of things, it’s easy to install apps and I’ve been running a yunohost server on my raspberry pi 4 for months now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weird things happen when you selfhost your blog (edit)</title>
      <link>https://lopeztel.xyz/blog/2020/10/16/weird-things-happen-when-you-selfhost-your-blog-edit/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2020 18:02:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lopeztel.xyz/blog/2020/10/16/weird-things-happen-when-you-selfhost-your-blog-edit/</guid>
      <description>Interesting, I managed to screw up my blog. Logging in is impossible through a web browser, I get the message:
 502 Bad Gateway
&amp;ndash; nginx This happened after messing around with the WP Reset plugin, apparently I deleted some custom table I shouldn’t have… Funnily enough I am still able to use the android app to create posts so not all hope is gone.
Weird things happen….
Edit: Turns out I couldn’t access the login screen for my site but could access the comments section (you know the one where you can approve new comments, then from there Dashboard was broken but I could access the menu Tools -&amp;gt; WP Reset).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Convenience vs Privacy (Round 1)</title>
      <link>https://lopeztel.xyz/blog/2020/09/04/convenience-vs-privacy-round-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2020 19:13:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lopeztel.xyz/blog/2020/09/04/convenience-vs-privacy-round-1/</guid>
      <description>A brief summary: I’ve been looking into privacy friendly alternatives to software most of us use or used in our everyday lives. To be more precise, an alternative to WhatsApp for communication within my family. Long story short: I lost this one…
A while back I switched from WhatsApp to Signal and kind of forced my family to switch as well, however:
Signal requires a phone number and depends on centralized servers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FOSS Donations</title>
      <link>https://lopeztel.xyz/blog/2020/08/26/foss-donations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 16:58:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lopeztel.xyz/blog/2020/08/26/foss-donations/</guid>
      <description>Let me start by saying that the purpose of this entry is not to say “Look at how selfless I am for donating money to FOSS organizations or projects” so, with that in mind, I will not list any specific quantities because that is not the point I am trying to make. Having written the proper disclaimer, let’s get to it:
My preferences In the past month I have written about my projects and experiences with FOSS, self hosting and even digital art.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing my yunohost wordpress blog</title>
      <link>https://lopeztel.xyz/blog/2020/08/22/optimizing-my-yunohost-wordpress-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2020 10:07:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lopeztel.xyz/blog/2020/08/22/optimizing-my-yunohost-wordpress-blog/</guid>
      <description>After my last update about my blog migration, basically all I did was install LiteSpeed Cache plugin and mess around with it.
For reference, lots of documentation goodness here
The most important part to note is that I kept getting bugged by both Google’s PageSpeed Insights and GTmetrix to enable text compression.
After some time reading about compression and Marco Saric’s blogpost, I tried to enable compression by adding some lines of code at the bottom of the .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migration to WordPress</title>
      <link>https://lopeztel.xyz/blog/2020/08/16/migration-to-wordpress/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Aug 2020 11:15:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lopeztel.xyz/blog/2020/08/16/migration-to-wordpress/</guid>
      <description>In recent days I’ve been busy trying to get my blog up and running on my cheapo Raspberry Pi + Yunohost server setup. The process was fun, so here’s a blog entry about migrating my blog (blogception?) from a writefreely instance to my self hosted wordpress instance.
Why though? To put it simply: because I can.
On a more serious note, my previous blog was hosted at qua.name and there was nothing wrong with it, but I really wanted to be able to have a bit more interaction, easy theming, and an overall a plug and play solution with a GUI.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Progress report on a more FOSS/FLOSS, decentralized digital life</title>
      <link>https://lopeztel.xyz/blog/2020/08/09/progress-report-on-a-more-foss-floss-decentralized-digital-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2020 06:00:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lopeztel.xyz/blog/2020/08/09/progress-report-on-a-more-foss-floss-decentralized-digital-life/</guid>
      <description>For context, let me refer to my very first entry, the idea was basically looking for alternatives, so here’s the long awaited progress report:
Changes already in place  Using Mastodon instead of Twitter Using Pixelfed instead of Instagram (On Android) Using NewPipe instead of YouTube, this one is quite cool, it has all the features you’d want: Download, Picture in Picture mode, Background Music reproduction… Using Writefreely and/or WordPress (Still haven’t decided) instead of other blogging platforms (On Android) Using Signal instead of WhatsApp, although that may change in the near future Using Jitsi Meet instead of Skype, Zoom, Google Hangouts Using Protonmail instead of Gmail (although not sure if FOSS/FLOSS, they maintain an OpenPGP library) (On Android) Using Simple Mobile Tools SMS Messenger instead of Google Messages Using Simple Mobile Tools Gallery instead of Google Photos Using Bitwarden instead of LastPass (On Android) Using andOTP (at least for personal stuff) Using F-Droid instead of the Google Play Store whenever possible  Changes in transition period  Self-hosted Nextcloud instead of Dropbox, Google Drive, One Drive… Self-hosted Gitea instead of Github (currently only mirroring) Self-hosted Piwigo gallery instead of Google Photos (more info on my setup here) Self-hosted email (problems with outgoing port 25) Self-hosted Synapse (Matrix server) in testing phase, could replace Signal by Element if tests show promising results Calendar synchronization using Nextcloud instead of Google Calendar (Android apps: Simple Mobile Tools Calendar, DAVX5 and OpenTasks) (On Android) Trying to use OsmAnd instead of Google Maps (This is by far the hardest change to be made)  Compromises  Facebook is still the platform where everyone plans events so I need that just to follow-up on them (not actively in use) Whatsapp and Facebook messenger as backup messaging (Trying to move friends and family over to Signal or Element) Can’t seem to get away from Microsoft: Teams, Outlook and Microsoft Authenticator are used for work  Day 11 of #100DaysToOffload</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Raspberry Pi server with yunohost</title>
      <link>https://lopeztel.xyz/blog/2020/08/08/my-raspberry-pi-server-with-yunohost/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Aug 2020 20:37:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lopeztel.xyz/blog/2020/08/08/my-raspberry-pi-server-with-yunohost/</guid>
      <description>I will try to make this entry resemble a tutorial, hopefully this ends up being useful to someone.
Why start over? I had been playing around with Open Media Vault before (see this entry for details), but it was mainly based on docker images and I could never get Nextcloud up and running (the closest I came was installing nextcloudpi, but I could never get the docker image to run using external storage).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thank you yunohost</title>
      <link>https://lopeztel.xyz/blog/2020/08/06/thank-you-yunohost/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2020 06:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lopeztel.xyz/blog/2020/08/06/thank-you-yunohost/</guid>
      <description>Ever since I started looking into the Fediverse, FOSS/FLOSS, privacy and self-hosting I was pleasantly surprised by how engaging and helpful the community can be.
As an example: in Fosstodon all my interactions have been very nice, from sharing random unrelated stuff to asking for advice on more technical matters everyone has always been helpful and willing to give advice.
Another great experience I had recently was related with the yunohost project (long story short, my Open Media Vault setup went down in flames, tutorial coming shortly), being kind of a big project one would think that as an individual, communication would be slow or hard, kind of like with companies as a consumer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The journey to self-hosting (on a Raspberrypi 4)</title>
      <link>https://lopeztel.xyz/blog/2020/07/07/the-journey-to-self-hosting-on-a-raspberrypi-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2020 20:12:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lopeztel.xyz/blog/2020/07/07/the-journey-to-self-hosting-on-a-raspberrypi-4/</guid>
      <description>Ever since discovering the Fediverse and reading toots from awesome people in Fosstodon, a little idea started to take shape in my head: perhaps its not that hard to self host, there are tons of tutorials and resources out there…And I need some alternative to google photos to share albums with my family back home
Hardware After some research and settled for a RaspberryPi server/NAS, now, the purists will say that it is not the ideal platform to host but I think it is perfect to get started and learn the basics or as a hobby, then you can move on to the big boy fancy server hardware.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
