<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>COVID-19 on Lopeztel&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://lopeztel.xyz/blog/tags/covid-19/</link>
    <description>Recent content in COVID-19 on Lopeztel&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2020 19:11:18 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lopeztel.xyz/blog/tags/covid-19/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Christmas 2020</title>
      <link>https://lopeztel.xyz/blog/2020/12/29/christmas-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2020 19:11:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lopeztel.xyz/blog/2020/12/29/christmas-2020/</guid>
      <description>This is meant to be a reflection on spending Christmas alone in one of the worst years for the planet in general.
I think it’s basically beating on a dead horse to say that 2020 has been horrible in general due to COVID-19, everyone has had it tough for a lot of reasons, from the worst (having lost a loved one or health issues) to the minor annoyances (like working from home).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on the pinebookpro (Part 3)</title>
      <link>https://lopeztel.xyz/blog/2020/11/17/thoughts-on-the-pinebookpro-part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2020 18:24:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lopeztel.xyz/blog/2020/11/17/thoughts-on-the-pinebookpro-part-3/</guid>
      <description>This is a follow-up on a previous entry
One step closer to daily driver!!
Working from home is possible with the pinebookpro I managed to connect to my workplace’s VPN, however it took some digging around: first of all, we have a Linux VPN package, so that’s already something, (kudos for showing Linux some love); you can choose to either install a .deb package, a .rpm package or build from source for either x86_64 or armhf architectures (basically just copies over some pre-compiled binaries), so far so good, everything great.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some thoughts about convenience and COVID-19</title>
      <link>https://lopeztel.xyz/blog/2020/04/18/some-thoughts-about-convenience-and-covid-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Apr 2020 19:55:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lopeztel.xyz/blog/2020/04/18/some-thoughts-about-convenience-and-covid-19/</guid>
      <description>I was just recently thinking given the recent COVID-19 situation, the world is not ready to prioritize what is really important.
It feels like no one really notices importance of services like running water, electricity and above all medical care. What I see on the news nowadays leads me to believe that no one really cares about anything as long as we’re not affected.
No one cared about COVID-19 until we couldn’t go out, until our Amazon or Aliexpress and overall cheap stuff from China couldn’t reach us in time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Skiing and COVID-19</title>
      <link>https://lopeztel.xyz/blog/2020/03/13/skiing-and-covid-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Mar 2020 19:52:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lopeztel.xyz/blog/2020/03/13/skiing-and-covid-19/</guid>
      <description>Some random thoughts on a recent failed ski trip and the global pandemic
Skiing First things first, I have absolutely no clue on how to ski, zero experience whatsoever, so naturally I had to sign up for my company’s Ski trip. In total there were 37 people in the group.
We got to a cabin close to a ski resort after a four and a half hour drive on Wednesday, all went well except for some icy paths on the way but that is another story (just don’t do summer tires and front 2 wheel drive on them, you’ll suffer a lot)</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
