<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Tutorial on Lopeztel&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://lopeztel.xyz/blog/tags/tutorial/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tutorial on Lopeztel&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2021 13:20:27 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lopeztel.xyz/blog/tags/tutorial/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Fooling around with bash scripts 2</title>
      <link>https://lopeztel.xyz/blog/2021/02/28/fooling-around-with-bash-scripts-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2021 13:20:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lopeztel.xyz/blog/2021/02/28/fooling-around-with-bash-scripts-2/</guid>
      <description>This is a follow-up to my previous entries: Fooling around with bash scripts, which I used as a base for Migration from Google Photos to Nextcloud and Piwigo
Since some of my old picture albums have old .mov, .mpg and .avi videos in them I decided to also convert them to .mp4 (piwigo can show them in the albums), so once again I tried came up with something to automate the task</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My (Neo)Vim Cheatsheet</title>
      <link>https://lopeztel.xyz/blog/2021/02/21/my-neovim-cheatsheet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2021 16:32:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lopeztel.xyz/blog/2021/02/21/my-neovim-cheatsheet/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been learning to use neovim for almost 3 weeks now and it has been fun, coming from VSCode I guess I was spoiled by the feature rich IDE/text editor, however there is beauty in the simplicity keyboard oriented (Neo)vim text editor
I’ve been trying to get all the useful keyboard shortcuts and commands I’ve found in a single place and I though this could be helpful for other noobs like me, fosstodon community was helpful and shared their Tips n’ Tricks as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migration from Google Photos to Nextcloud and Piwigo</title>
      <link>https://lopeztel.xyz/blog/2021/02/13/migration-from-google-photos-to-nextcloud-and-piwigo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2021 18:59:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lopeztel.xyz/blog/2021/02/13/migration-from-google-photos-to-nextcloud-and-piwigo/</guid>
      <description>Getting the pictures First step was downloading all my pictures from Google Photos, so I went to Google Takeout which is the way to download all the data the big G has on you. For now I selected only the data in Google Photos but if I had wanted to I could’ve downloaded potentially everything.
Just for context I didn’t have that much in Google Photos, around 45 GB total, not bad</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My transition from VSCode to Neovim</title>
      <link>https://lopeztel.xyz/blog/2021/01/28/my-transition-from-vscode-to-neovim/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 19:32:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lopeztel.xyz/blog/2021/01/28/my-transition-from-vscode-to-neovim/</guid>
      <description>I’ve always liked the idea of using a tiling window manager and customizing the hell out of it, you know, the kind of stuff you see by searching for the linuxPorn hashtag… My main problem with them is that I am very very used to GUIs, while I am fairly competent on a terminal, I have never learned to use emacs or vim. I am in the middle of transitioning to CLI based programs, on a previous post I described ncspot and mpsyt, I’ve also been looking at gomuks and ranger</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
